BRIAN CAO

Software Engineer

🗡 fullstackbriancao@gmail.com 📞 (657) 206-2005

Garden Grove, CA — @CaoBeee https://github.com/CaoBeee/

SUMMARY

Skilled and dedicated Software Engineer with specifically 2+ years of experience in software engineering and overall 8+ years as an office professional. My diverse skillset allows me to work as a diligent, coordinated team member with the ability to work self-sufficiently or within teams, whether it be traditional or cross-functional, with little to no supervision. My goal as a Software Engineer is continual growth in a field that is ever-changing and to use that growth, whether it be individually or as a team, to build a product/service that will make an impact on the world by solving issues that affect our daily lives on a larger scale through technology.

EXPERIENCE

Software Engineer

July 2022 - Nov 2022

MiVet | Irvine, CA

MiVet is a fullstack web application whose mission is to streamline equine veterinary care through technology.

- · Developed a calendar interface that allows the end-user to view the user's availability using React.js library.
- · Optimized software application by developing an efficient SQL database system with stored procedures and utilizing SQL Server Management Studio for streamlined data retrieval and manipulation.
- · Designed and developed a robust RESTful API with .NET Core framework and C# to efficiently integrate and manage data flow between client-side requests and the database.
- · Used Git and GitHub for team collaboration and communication, resulting in a notable decrease in software bugs.
- · Consistently participated in daily stand-up meetings and peer code reviews, fostering a collaborative and agile team environment.

Maintenance Data Analyst

Apr 2017 - Apr 2021

United States Air Force | Holloman AFB, NM

- · Onboarded and managed a team of five analysts in the process of evaluation of maintenance management that improved efficiency, team productivity and overall data accuracy and proficiency.
- · Streamlined reporting, data accuracy monitoring, and encouraged recommendations resulting in a significant decrease in preparation time.
- · Managed team projects, created and implemented standard operating procedures to improve data accuracy.
- · Supervised corrective action plans resulting in increased equipment uptime and reduced material consumption.

Document Conversion Specialist

Sept 2014 - Dec 2015

ViaTRON Systems Inc | Gardena, CA

- · Processed digital images using Kodak OCR and Kofax software to meet quality control standards.
- · Performed data entry and review for accurate documentation.
- Archived and maintained documents and databases using Microsoft Excel and Access.
- · Prepared procedural and user software documentation.
- · Collaborated with stakeholders to resolve software issues in compliance with standards.

PROJECTS

Face Detection Website

React.js, Express.js, Node.js, PostgreSQL | https://facerecognitionbrain-caobeee.onrender.com/

Using ClarifAl's face detection AI model, this project detects faces within user-input images via a URL.

Shopping List

HTML, CSS, Javascript, Firebase | https://cart-app-caobeee.netlify.app/

A mobile web application that uses the power of Firebase's real-time database to provide users with a streamlined and responsive experience for data storage and retrieval on-the-go.

For additional projects not listed on my resume, visit my GitHub profile @CaoBeee https://github.com/CaoBeee/

SKILLS

Programming Languages

- · HTML
- · CSS
- Javascript
- · C#
- · SOL

Technologies

- · React.js
- · Bootstrap
- · .NET Core
- · Express.is Node.is
- · Next.js

Database

- · Microsoft SQL Server
- · PostgreSQL

Tools

- Netlify
- Render
- · Visual Studio Code · Visual Studio
- · GitHub
- SSMS
- DBeaver
- · Postman

Other

· Secret Level Security Clearance (DoD), [2017-2021]

EDUCATION

High School Diploma

South High | Torrance, CA

June 2011

References

Available upon request.